# FAHIM RUSTAMY

Route 212, Richlandtown, PA 18955

 $(610) \cdot 653 \cdot 3925 \diamond faheemrustamy@gmail.com \diamond https://rustamyf.github.io$ 

#### **SUMMARY**

Engineering Ph.D. with a focus on probabilistic modeling, machine learning, and structural risk assessment with 5+ years of professional and academic experience. Proficient Data Scientist with a strong mathematical and statistical background with extensive knowledge and expertise in cloud computing and machine learning.

- AWS Certified Machine Learning Specialty
- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- Certified Tensorflow Developer

- AWS Certified Data Analytics Specialty
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

### **EDUCATION**

#### Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA

August 2015 - May 2021

Ph.D. & M.Sc. in Engineering/Probabilistic Modeling of Engineering Structures

Relevant Coursework: Deep-learning, introduction to machine learning, random vibration, engineering probability, Data Mining, Engineering Risk Analysis.

## Kabul University, Kabul, Afghanistan

Jan 2013

B.Sc. in Civil Engineering

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Lehigh University, ATLSS Center

Research Assistant

August 2015 - Present Bethlehem, PA

- · Developed synthetic seismic ground motions records using stochastic processes method for the Eastern US.
- · Proposed a new method for evaluating the fragility of engineering structures using Artificial Neural Networks.
- · Developed system reliability of power systems using MCS and Logistic Regression Methods.
- · Proposed a simulation method using damage data and multivariate random samples for system resilience.
- · Presented two days of training on short circuit time-history analysis for ConED staff in their NYC office.
- · Taught five undergraduate courses as a teacher assistant.

### **State Corps Engineering**

 $Project\ Manager$ 

October 2012 - May 2015 Kabul, Afghanistan

- · Managed US Army \$30+ million worth infrastructure projects. Prepared contract drawings and project specifications for the client.
- · Communicated with the client (USACE) and site teams to correct construction QC and safety deficiencies.
- · Completed the projects on time and was awarded several completion awards from USACE & government.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages Matlab, Python (Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, scikit-learn, Flask and Tensorflow)
Cloud Sagemaker, Athena, Redshift, S3, EMR, Hadoop, AWS Lambda, ECR, Kubernetes
Kinesis and other AWS technologies.

ML Models Linear and Logistic Regression, XGBoost, Neural Network, RNN, CNN, and KNN, using

Tensorflow and Sagemaker frameworks

Others LaTex, SQL, Docker, GIT and Linux

## FELLOWSHIPS AND AWARDS

- Fulbright Fellowship (was selected from 5000 applicants)
- Gibson fellowship (was awarded for excellence in research)